Guide to the Patricia Pierce, Dean of Academic Life, Yale College, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Patricia Pierce, dean of academic life, Yale College, records
1971-1988
RU 579
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.25
(5 boxes)
The records consist of office files dean of academic life at Yale College documenting students, teaching fellows, committees, disciplinary actions, and the Women's Studies Program of Yale College.
Yale College (1887- ). Dean's Office
Pierce, Patricia Dawes
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-B (YRG 9-B), Records of deputy, associate, and assistant deans of Yale College.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of office files dean of academic life at Yale College documenting students, teaching fellows, committees, disciplinary actions, and the Women's Studies Program of Yale College.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by subject.
Deans (Education); Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale College (1887- ). Administration; Yale College (1887- ). Dean's Office; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Students
- Records of Patricia Pierce as dean of academic life, 1971-1988; Accession 1990-A-022
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2024.
  - Executive Committee Records, 1985-1986
    - Chrono file: Police Reports (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Referred cases: chronological (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous letters (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Social Function Reports (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
    - Monthly Residential College Crime Reports (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Committee 1984-1985 Log: both versions (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Woodbridge Hall: Blocking protests -- Documents
      - 1986 Apr 14 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - 1986 Apr 16 (Box 1, Folder 12 - 15)
      - 1986 Apr 25 (Box 1, Folder 16 - 20)
    - First Committee meeting material: Originals (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 230 Prospect Street: Break-in, 1985 September 26 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Executive Committee Records, 1984-1985
    - Sexual assault: Complaint, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Executive Committee Records, 1986-1987
    - Referred cases (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Police Reports (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Monthly Residential College Crime Reports (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Social Function Reports (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Documents: miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Undergraduate Regulations (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Undergraduate Regulations on Alcholic Beverages (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Off-Campus furniture: resolved (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - 451 College Street ("Interference with University Functions ") (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - 451 College: Investments Office sit-in (Box 2, Folder 94 - 95)
  - Teaching Fellows, 1986-1987
    - African Languages (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Afro-American Studies (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - American Studies (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Anthropology (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Archaealogy (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Astronomy (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Biology (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Chemistry (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Classics (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Computer Science (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - East Asian Languages (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Economics (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Engf ish (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Engineering and Applied Science (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Epidemology and Public Health (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - French (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Film Studies (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Geology and Geophysics (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Germanic Languages (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - History (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - History of Art (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Humanities (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Italian (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Linguistics (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Literature Major / Comparative Literature (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Mathematics (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Medieval (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Molecular Biophysics and Biochemistry (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Music (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Near Eastern Languages and Literature (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Philosophy (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Physics (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - PEW (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Political Science (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Psychology (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Religious Studies (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Renaissance (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Residential College Seminars (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Slavic (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Sociology (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - SOM (School of organization and Management) (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Spanish (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Statistics (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Theater Studies (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Women's Studies (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Miscellaneous Departments (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Teaching Fellows, 1987-1988
    - African Languages (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Afro-American Studies (Box 4, Folder 146)
    - American Studies (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Anthropology (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Astronomy (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - Biology (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Chemistry (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - Classics (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Computer Science (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - East Asian Languages and Literature (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Economics (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Engineering and Applied Science (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - English (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Epidemology and Public Health (Box 4, Folder 157A)
    - Film Studies (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - French (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Geology and Geophysics (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - German (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - History (Box 4, Folder 162 - 163)
    - History of Art (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - History of Medicine (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Humanities (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Italian (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Linguistics (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Literature Major / Comparative Literature (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Mathematics (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Medieval Studies (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Molecular Biology and Biochemistry (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - Music (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Near Eastern Languages and Literature (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Organization and Management (Box 4, Folder 175)
    - Philosophy (Box 4, Folder 176)
    - Physics (Box 4, Folder 177)
    - Political Science (Box 4, Folder 178)
    - Psychology (Box 4, Folder 179)
    - Religious Studies (Box 4, Folder 180)
    - Renaissance Studies (Box 4, Folder 181)
    - Residential College Seminars (Box 4, Folder 182)
    - Slavic (Box 4, Folder 183)
    - Sociology (Box 4, Folder 184)
    - Spanish and Portuguese (Box 4, Folder 185)
    - Statistics (Box 4, Folder 186)
    - Theater Studies (Box 4, Folder 187)
    - women's Studies (Box 4, Folder 188)
    - Miscellaneous Departments (Box 4, Folder 189)
  - Women's Studies Program
    - 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 191 - 192)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 193 - 194)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 195 - 197)
    - Council
      - 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 198)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 199)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 200)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 5, Folder 201)
    - Budget, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - Requests for information, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 203)
    - Outline, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    - "Women at Yale, A Statistical Profile 1969-1979" (Box 5, Folder 205)
    - Program Activities, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 206)
    - Budget, 1980-1983 (Box 5, Folder 207 - 210)
    - Budget: Correspondence and background, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 211)
    - Conference, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 212)
    - Dinner with Women Scholars, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 213)
    - General, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 214)
    - Articles, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 215)
    - National and Regional Meetings, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 216)
    - Dinner, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 217)
    - Grant Proposal, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1983 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    - Yale Courses, 1971-1976 (Box 5, Folder 220)
    - Forms, memoranda, 1971-1976 (Box 5, Folder 221)
    - Resources, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 222)
    - Course and Course Curriculum, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 223)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Grant material, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 224)